<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Portfolio on Jaya Varshini Prabakar</title>
    <link>https://jayavarshini6.github.io/MyPortfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science Portfolio on Jaya Varshini Prabakar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jayavarshini6.github.io/MyPortfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: HMO Health Care Plan Predictive Analysis</title>
      <link>https://jayavarshini6.github.io/MyPortfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jayavarshini6.github.io/MyPortfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Collaborated with team of 5 to create an application that estimates the expensive patient in the healthcare system and provide actionable insight to reduce the healthcare cost. Cleaned over 7 thousand patient records from 7 Northeastern US states such as Connecticut,Maryland,Massachusetts,New Jersey,New York,Pennsylvania and Rhode Island. Build visualizations using R to dertermine the factors leading to higher medical cost. Optimized Linear,Logit Regeression,Neural Network, Association Rule, Decision Tree, Random Forest and Support Vector Machine to reach the best model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Breast Cancer Prediction Machine Learning Model</title>
      <link>https://jayavarshini6.github.io/MyPortfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jayavarshini6.github.io/MyPortfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>This is my self study project where I build Machine Learning Model for predicting Breast Cancer using kaggle dataset.The model I build will be helpful in selecting whether the tumour is begnin or malignant. Build visualizations using python to determine which characteristics of tumor determines its severity of breast cancer. Achieved 92.2% accuracy in determing the type of breast cancer using Decision Tree Classifier model. Performed Hyperparameter tuning on all models to avoid overfitting and to achieve ideal model architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 3: Car Dealership Management System</title>
      <link>https://jayavarshini6.github.io/MyPortfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jayavarshini6.github.io/MyPortfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Worked in team of 4 to build a database management system to display available cars, car owner details, customer credit score to the customer support officer. Enforced integrity using integrity constraint and database triggers. Gathered requirements from business analysis, developed Logical and Conceptual model using draw.io. Improved database performance and optimized SQL queries by 70% loading speed using database defragmentation. Link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://jayavarshini6.github.io/MyPortfolio/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jayavarshini6.github.io/MyPortfolio/about/</guid>
      <description>Data Science and Health Analytics are my passion.My name is Jaya and I&amp;rsquo;m an Applied Data Science graduate student at Syracuse University, New York. A little about me I&amp;rsquo;m a curious person and love to learn new fields, that curiosity encouraged me to take a huge leap and made me to move half way across the world to do my Masters, packing my whole life in three large suitcases. Currently I&amp;rsquo;m in my secound semester and enjoying every second of my grad school!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://jayavarshini6.github.io/MyPortfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jayavarshini6.github.io/MyPortfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>You can connect with me through these platforms.
Platform URL LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jayavarshini/ GitHub: https://github.com/jayavarshini6 University MailId jprabaka@syr.edu GMail: jayavarshini463@gmail.com </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
